Guide to the American Dance Festival Records, circa 1924-1985, bulk 1934-1977 ADF.015
American Dance Festival Archives
- Printed Material, 1930-1977 (Box 69)
  - Bibliographies and Catalogs, 1930-1974 and undated, 0.33 Linear Feet (Box 69)
    Contains dance and music bibliographies and dance film and costume catalogs. Most of the bibliographies were compiled for student and ADF community usage during the ADF School. In some years, Connecticut College compiled a "Library Reporter" bibliography of dance books especially for the ADF School during the summer. Other bibliographies may have been compiled by ADF faculty for summer courses at the ADF School or by ADF directors in their own teaching endeavors. Catalogs represent a sampling of film, music, and costume catalogs that ADF used to order literature or costume for courses or special film series and lectures.
  - Directories and Mailing Lists, 1937-1977, 1.0 Linear Feet (Box 69)
    Contains phone and address directories for participants in the ADF School, workshops, and performances, as well as faculty and staff members. Most years contain directories for both home and summer (at ADF) addresses and phone numbers, and most all directories identify the individual's occupation.
    - 1937-1952 (Box 69)
    - 1953-1977 (Box 70)
  - Ephemera, 1957-1977, 13 folders (Box 70)
    Contains student meal tickets, identification cards, ADF letterhead, small flyers circulated to advertise the performance season, and a sampling of materials generated by the Friends' organization in New London.
  - Invitations, 1958-1977, 13 folders (Box 70)
    Contains invitations issued by ADF to various members of the ADF community, such as faculty, staff, performers, students, as well as members of the Connecticut College staff and potential donors. Types of events include open houses, opening parties at the beginning of the season, post-performance parties and receptions, brunches, cocktail receptions, lecture demonstrations, and performances.
  - Labanotation, 1954-1977 and undated, 12 folders (Box 70)
    Contains press releases, scores, textbooks, correspondence, and notes referring to Labanotation.
  - Mailers and Brochures, 1948-1977, 30 folders (Box 70)
    Contains printed materials sent to members of the ADF community, prospective students, and potential ticket buyers, including performance and school announcements, schedules of performances, ticket order forms, informational brochures, schedules and calendars, school bulletins and catalogs, and advertising flyers and posters that were sent through the mail. Form letters are not included in this series.
    - 1948-1962 (Box 70)
    - 1963-1977 (Box 71)
  - Playbills, 1950, 1952, 1956, 1964-1977, 17 folders (Box 71)
    Playbills contain artist information, school and festival information, and advertisements.
  - Posters, 1954, 1959-1968, 9 folders (Box 71)
  - Posters, 1959-1960, 1962-1964, 1966-1974, 1976 (Box OS2)
  - Programs, 1934-1977, 1.0 Linear Feet (Box 71)
    - 1934-1960 (Box 71)
    - 1961-1977 (Box 72)
    - Two volumes of bound programs, 1958-1966 (Box 73)
  - Season Reports and Statistics, 1948-1977, 0.5 Linear Feet (Box 72)
    Contains narrative and statistical reports of both the ADF School and festival performances. School statistics include enrollment numbers, average ages of students, and their geographical distribution.
    - 1948-1963 (Box 72)
    - 1964-1977 (Box 74)
  - Schedules and Calendars, 1948-1977, 30 folders (Box 74)
    Contains schedules and calendars circulated internally among the ADF students, faculty, and performers, and publicly to members of the ADF community and prospective students and ticket buyers. Includes schedules and calendars of performances, ticket order forms, school schedules, opening week schedules, weekly schedules, meal schedules, schedules of events open to the public, and lecture series schedules.
- Awards and Tributes, 1959-1974 and undated, 13 folders (Box 74)
  Contains correspondence informing interested parties of the death of Ruth Bloomer, donations to the scholarship fund established in her honor, and acknowledgements of these donations, correspondence regarding the loss of Doris Humphrey and materials regarding a Doris Humphrey memorial program, funding requests and acknowledgements regarding the Louis Horst Memorial Fund and the 1964 Louis Horst Memorial Concert, materials regarding the 1973 Jose Limon Memorial Film Program, and materials regarding the Simon Sadoff Award to acknowledge the contributions and achievements of musical conductors in dance.
  - Ruth Bloomer Fund and Memorial, 1959 (Box 74)
  - Doris Humphrey, 1959-1960 (3 folders) (Box 74)
  - Louis Horst, 1961 (Box 74)
  - Louis Horst, 1964 (4 folders) (Box 74)
  - Jose Limon, 1972-1973 (2 folders) (Box 74)
  - Simon Sadoff, 1974 (Box 74)
  - Ruth Bloomer, undated (Box 74)
- Other Organizations, 1942-1977, 0.42 Linear Feet (Box 74)
  Contains printed materials concerning organizations with parallel or related activities (e.g., Jacob's Pillow and the Dance Notation Bureau).